Preliminary Inventory to the Stephen Denis Kertesz Papers, 1932-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
Stephen Denis Kertesz Papers
1932-1986
86010
Hoover Institution Archives
180 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize folder, 1 album box, 1 microfilm reel, 1 phonotape, 2 phonotape cassettes (76 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to the politics, economy and diplomacy of Hungary, minority problems involving Hungary or Hungarians, the Paris Peace Conference of 1946, modern diplomatic history, and international relations.
Kertesz, Stephen D. (Stephen Denis), 1904-1986.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to the politics, economy and diplomacy of Hungary, minority problems involving Hungary or Hungarians, the Paris Peace Conference of 1946, modern diplomatic history, and international relations.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Paris Peace Conference (1946); Diplomats--Hungary.; Hungarians in foreign countries.; Hungary--Economic conditions.; Hungary--Foreign relations.; Hungary--Politics and government--20th century.; Hungary.; International relations.; Minorities--Hungary.; Phonotapes.; World politics--20th century.; World War, 1939-1945--Hungary.; World War, 1939-1945--Peace.; World War, 1939-1945.
- 21st Century (Folder 2)
- Bunte, Special 1945-85 Forty Years in Pictures (MAGAZINE)
- Quentine L. Quade. The US and Wars of National Liberation (BOOKLET)
- Europe. United States of Europe. Correspondence (Folder 3)
- German Reunification (Folder 4)
- Diplomatic Problems in Africa (Folder 5)
- Black Folder pasted up clippings
- State. (NEWSLETTER OPENED AT Page 3), June 1985
- Folder without heading in this order (Folder 6)
- Beige Vynil folder letters and clippings
- Diplomacy Material to be considered in the last chapter (Folder 7)
- Files related to next book project (Box 11, Bundle Bundle XVII)
  - Diplomacy (TYPED TEXTS) (Folder 1)
  - Diplomacy. Sources, Diplomacy (Folder 2)
  - Diplomacy Introductory texts. Literature (Folder 3)
  - Modern Times. Marked II, (Fifteenth Century to 1945) (Folder 4)
  - Contemporary Predicament. Marked III (Folder 5)
  - The Future. Marked IV (Folder 6)
  - Unmarked green folder with typed texts (Folder 7)
  - Visual Aids (Folder 8)
  - S. Kertesz: The Interdependent World...., August 31, 1976 (Folder 9)
  - Texts to check. International Relations in Antiquity. Diplomacy in the Middle Ages (Folder 10)
    General note
    THESE ARE FILES RELATED TO PROF.KERTESZ' PLANNED NEXT BOOK
- The Revue of Politics. Vol.42. No.2. (BOOKLET), April 1980 (Bundle Bundle XVIII)
- American Diplomacy (Reprint, open at p.231)
- Diplomacy, Working copy, (3 books with missing pages) (Folder 1)
- Südosteuropa Mitteilungen. Nr. 1/2 25.Jahrgang (BOOK), 1985
- Quest for Peach through Diplomacy, with notes (Folder 2)
- Book reviews. Reviews and Announcements on the Books, ONE FOLDER (Box 12, Bundle Bundle XIX)
- MISCELLANEOUS PROJECTS PRECEDING LAST ILLNES (Bundle Bundle XX)
  - Hacker Material (Folder 1)
  - material belongs to Bundle CXXXIX (Folder 2)
  - Raeffa. Typed texts (Folder 3)
  - material belongs to Bundle CXXXIX (Folder 4)
  - N.D. University Press to Xerox at Department (Folder 5)
- MISCELLANEOUS (Bundle Bundle XXI)
  - The US and the Crisis in the Liberal Prescription for World Order by Harold K. Jacobson. (MIMEOGRAPHED)
  - Possible Lecture Topic (Folder 1)
  - Shaping of Foreign Policy in the US and USSR (Folder 2)
  - Book recommendations (Folder 3)
- News Release (REPRINT) (Bundle Bundle XXII)
- Kissinger sources (Folder 1)
- Kissinger's Diplomacy., 1975-76 (Folder 2)
- State Department, Kissinger Texts (Folder 3)
- Remarks by the Honorable Henry A. Kissinger)REPRINT) (Box 13, Bundle Bundle XXIII)
- Contribution to the Austrian Yearbook (Folder 1)
- Misc. Handwritten material found in this order (Folder 2)
- Notes on Koonig's Book (Folder 3)
- Bohlen Material (Folder 4)
- Notes to be Classified (Folder 5)
- Material to be organized (Folder 6)
- Typed text to be classified and organized (Folder 7)
- Categorization of Materials... Old Categories (Folder 8)
- Unmarked folder with handwritten drafts (Folder 9)
- To be used - read material. Notes. Unused texts, US Security, December 1925-76 (Folder 10)
- General Idea texts., 1976
- Contemporary State System and Security (Folder 12)
- Notes on NATO, European Unity, International Publications and related questions, 1961-62 (Folder 13)
- Summit Material Index (Box 13-14, Bundle Bundle XXIV)
- President Nixon's Visit to China (Folder 1)
- Moscow Summit, May 1972 (Folder 2)
- Nixon-Kissinger Summit Meetings. (Before Peking and Moscow), 1971-72 (Folder 3)
- Kissinger and his role., 1971-72 (Folder 4)
- Unmarked folder - clippings and booklet (Folder 5)
- Political Consequences of a Divided World. Lecture, 1962 (Bundle Bundle XXV, Folder 1)
- Hungarian Diplomacy in the Four-Power Politics of the Postwar Era. Lecture in Munich (?) (Published later), June 16, 1977 (Folder 2)
- Political and Moral Issues in the American Policy of Liberation. Lecture in Sierra Club, Chicago, March 20, 1959 (Folder 3)
- Introductory Speeches (Persons who visited N.D.) (Folder 4)
- List of Addresses at Conferences and Lectures., 1948-78 (Folder 5)
- The Danube Basin and Hungary up to 1947. A survey. (TYPEWRITTEN) (Folder 6)
- Development of the Hungarian Constitution (Box 14-15, Bundle Bundle XXVI, Folder 1)
- Party Politics and the Role of outside forces in Postwar Hungary (Typewritten) (Folder 2)
- Introductory and Closing Remarks. Short Addresses at Conferences, 1950-7 (Folder 3)
- Radio and Television Addresses and Short Statements., 1950-19(?) (Folder 4)
- Addresses on Hungary, the Soviet Conquest of East Central Europe and the Hungarian Revolution, How Stalin conquered his Satellite Empire, 1950-58 (Folder 5)
- Magyar beszédek. Amerika és a Hidegháboru. Thanksgiving jelentösege, 1956 Novembereben (Folder 6)
- Misc. loose papers found in this grouping (Folder 7)
- Discussion with Students. Thursday 8 p.m. Salm Hall, Notes, 1956 (Folder 8)
- Justice and Law in a Free Society, Lake Placid, 1957 (Folder 9)
- The Trend Towards a World Order. An address delivered at N.D
- Organizing for World Order - International Organization and World Order. Western and Soviet Material
- India and the US. Bloomington, Analysis of the National Power, April 28, 1960 1960 (Folder 10)
- 10a. The Midwest Fulbright conference on Higher Education. (MIMEOGRAPHED TEXT AND TYPEWRITTEN ORIGINAL)
- The Berlin Crisis., 1961 (Folder 11)
- Racial States in the Middle East (Folder 12)
- Misc. Typewritten drafts found in this order (Folder 13)
- Wiesbaden, Sept. 8-12, 1963 (Folder 14)
- Erasmus Conference. The International Conditions of Erasmus' Time. The question of just war., December 1969 (Folder 15)
- Unidentified folder (Folder 16)
- Internal Problems of the Communist Bloc (Folder 17)
- Mindszenty levelezése és beszédanyaga, ONE FOLDER (Box 15, Bundle Bundle XXVII)
- Notes mainly in the late 1950s (Box 15-16, Bundle Bundle XXVIII, Folder 1)
- Kertesz: Alternative Futures for the United Nations Systems (MIMEOGRAPHE) (Folder 2)
- Moral Principles and the International Law (Folder 3)
- Notes on Diplomacy, European Integration and other topics, mainly in 1958-59. (SMALLER BROWN FOLDER) (Folder 4)
- Lakosságcsere, Habilitacios elóadás ben, 1945 (Folder 5)
- Underdeveloped areas. Population problems. Planning (Folder 6)
- Teacher in Institution and Higher Learning (Folder 7)
- There is no No.8
- Nato Letter. Special number on Iceland (MAGAZINE) (Folder 9)
- America's Future, Discussed in the 1960s (Folder 10)
- Ideals, Reflections, Ideas and Wisdom. World Problems (Folder 11)
- Minority Material. Magántanári Probaelöadás., 1945 (Folder 12)
- Misc. Loose material found in this order (Folder 13)
- Mixed Material and Memoirs (Box 16-17, Bundle Bundle XXIX, Folder 1)
- Mixed Material (Folder 2)
- Mundus vult. decipi. Contradictions in American Diplomacy. My comments on Schlesinger's and May's paper in 1965 (Folder 3)
- Unidentified folder, clippings (Folder 4)
- The 1971 IPAC Transitional Training Project. (BOOKLET) (Folder 5)
- Universitetsforlage, 3/4 Cooperation and Conflict (BOOKLET), 1973 (Folder 6)
- Foreign Policy Issues. Articles, (Mainly 1968, 69, 70) (Folder 7)
- Misc. Clippings found in this order (Folder 8)
- Kárász, Communists in Europe. (MIMEOGRAPHED), Oct. 20, 1950 (Folder 9)
- Teleki: Memorial speech on January 20, 1952 (Folder 10)
- Report on the Fordham University Carnegie Endowment Conference on US initiatives to advance international Peace (Folder 11)
- Witness of Collapsing Worlds. (TYPEWRITTEN INDEX NOTES) (Box 17, Bundle Bundle XXX, Folder 1)
- Marked I, II, 1914-1939 (Folder 2)
- WW II and US Policy since WW II. Predicament of US Diplomacy. CIA. Making US Foreign Policy. - Life in exile. - US Stature in World Affirs. Marked III (Folder 3)
- Changing Europe and Changing USA. Marked V and VI (Folder 4)
- European and US Universities. Social Sciences and Qualification. Teachers in the US. Academicians, newsprogramers and Decision Makers. Values. Marked VI (Folder 5)
- Short notes. Marked X (Folder 6)
- How Foreign Policy is Formed in the National State. Several pieces with notes on lectures (Box 17-18, Bundle Bundle XXXI, Folder 1)
- Misc. clippings and folders found in this order (Folder 2)
- Human Rights in Perspective. Speech in Oct. 1968 and Material (Folder 3)
- Mainly Hungarian Material (Folder 4)
- Material to Memoranda and Part III. (PRINTED OR MIMEOGRAPHED MATERIAL) (Folder 5)
- Meaning of Interdependence (Folder 6)
- Concluding Chapter Material III. Lessons of the Past and New Factors in the First Period of Global History (Folder 7)
- Index (TYPEWRITTEN) (Box 18-19, Bundle Bundle XXXII, Folder 1)
- The Impact of WW I on Europe. The Interwar Years. Paris The Hague Marked I, 1914-1939 1926-28, 1929 (Folder 2)
- 1935-37 Rockefeller Fellowship. The American Society. Marked IIa (Folder 3)
- The Changing American Society under the Roosevelt Administration. Strength and weeknesses of the American Social, Political and Economic System from Truman to Ford. Yale and Yale Marked II, 1935-36 1948-50 (Folder 4)
- Making US Foreign Policy. UN, Vietnam, China, CIA. US Foreign Policy since WW II. Life in Exile (Folder 5)
- IV National Priorities in USA. Changing America in Recent Years (Folder 6)
- IV. Changing Europe. TYPED FILE: Conversations in Europe in 1958-59 and in 1965-66. Western and Eastern Europe (Folder 7)
- VI. European and US Universities. Teaching and Teachers in the US (Folder 8)
- VII. The Role of Ethnic Groups in the American Society (Folder 9)
- VIII. General Ideas. Acute problems of the Contemporary Crisis. MS pp. 9-11 (Folder 10)
- IX. The Future as seen in 1977-78. US and World Problems (Folder 11)
- X. Mixed Material (Folder 12)
- Part I. 18th Century, 19th Century and the American Regime (Box 19, Bundle Bundle XXXIII, Folder 1)
- Headline Series, Number 154. US Trade and the Common Market by W. Clayton (BOOKLET) (Folder 2)
- 92d Congress, 2d Session. National Security Policy and the Changing Worldpower Aligment. (REPRINT) (Folder 3)
- Black spiral binder with handwritten notes and clippings (Folder 4)
- Bookreviews to be com.?...ed (Folder 5)
- Misc. Reprints and booklets found in this order (Folder 6)
- 1976-66 (Folder 7)
- Illusions and Reality. Project and Table of Contents. Supplementary Notes to Part III. Table of contents of the collection of Material (Folder 8)
- Misc. Congressional reprints, found in this order (Box 20-21, Bundle Bundle XXXIV, Folder 1)
- Misc. Bulletins, found in this order (Folder 2)
- Black ringbinder with notes and clippings (Folder 3)
- I.a. Development of the Modern State System (Folder 4)
- IB. The Congress of Vienna, 1814-15 (Folder 5)
- Comparative Papers, 1815, 1919, 1946 (Folder 6)
- Congress of Vienna Papers (Folder 7)
- Ic. Maps of Europe by Treaty, Vol.I. Treaties Concluded between March 30. 1814 and April 4, 1826 (Folder 8)
- Id. The Concert of Europe and Nineteenth Century Developments (Folder 9)
- - 2 WW I and the Conference of Versailles Universalism v. Regionalism, (1919) (Folder 10)
- WW I. Interwar Years. Versailles (Folder 11)
- Black Ringbinder - Congressional reports, etc (Box 21, Bundle Bundle XXXV)
- Misc. Reprints and bookreviews
- Bartok, Barankovics, Auer (Box 22-23, Bundle Bundle XXXVI, Folder 1)
- Jelentösebb Aktamásolatok. Magyarország Háborus Felelössége (Folder 2)
- Agrarian reform and other measures. Severance of Consular Relations with Hungary in 1950. The Vogeler Case. Hungarian Peace Movement, US Policy toward Hungary in the early postwar period. US-Hungarian relations (Folder 3)
- öszén készült összefoglalás. Egy emberöltö története, 1945 (Folder 4)
- A magyar külpolitika ellenállási törekvései. Teleki-Ghyczy - Kállay - Lakatos, 1939-1944 (Folder 5)
- Grolier Encyclopedia. Hungary (Folder 6)
- Policy of Liberation, and after Government in Exile, 1952 (Folder 7)
- Sajtoarchivum Erdelyi Magyar Sajtoszemle (Folder 8)
- Mayda Material Communist Constitutions, Hungary (Folder 9)
- Hungarian Material Bibliography - Sources, Karstan Committee Hearings, 1945-59 (Folder 10)
- Assembly of Captive European Nations. Tentative Draft, ACEN's interpretation of the New Soviet Strategy. 56, (MIMEOGRAPHED), Sept.11 (Box 23, Bundle Bundle XXXVII, Folder 1)
- Kis Magyar Könyvtár. IV. Kovrig Béla, Magyar Társadalompolitika, 1920-41 (Folder 2)
- Kis Magyar Könyvtár. V. Kovrig Béla, Magyar Társadalompolitika, 1920-45 (Folder 3)
- Kis Magyar Könyvtár. Horváth Barna, A Magyar Közjog kis tükre (Folder 4)
- Hungary at the Conference of Paris. Vol. IV (BOUND BOOK) (Box 24, Bundle Bundle XXXVIII, Folder 1)
- Misc. Executive Agreement Series Armistice. (BOOKLETS AND REPRINTS FROM HUNGARIAN MINISTRY FOR FOREIGN AFFAIRS) (Folder 2)
- La Hongrie et la Conference de Paris. Tome 1. Les rapports internationaux de la Hongrie avant la Conference de Paris (Folder 3)
- Aide Memoire of the Hungarian Government Presented to the 21 nations assembled in Conference in Paris for the Drafting of the Peace Treaties with Annexes (GREY FOLDER BOX) (Folder 4)
- Hungary and the Conference of Paris Vol.II (Folder 5)
- Treaties of Peace with Italy, Bulgaria, Hungary, Roumania and Finland (BLUE BOOK) (Folder 6)
- Map (Folder 7)
- WITHDRAWN (Bundle Bundle XXXIX)
  - Papers Concerning Golan Drive 200, Key Biscayne
- Chronological and Topical Background Material. Diplomacy in a Whirlpool. Important source material especially for WW II and the early postwar period, (ONE YELLOW FOLDER WITH LOOSE TYPEWRITTEN SHEETS AND CLIPPINGS) (Box 25, Bundle Bundle XL)
- Danubian or larger Federation (Box 25-27, Bundle Bundle XLI, Folder 1)
- Kertesz: Limitations and Failures of Diplomacy (TYPEWRITTEN) (Folder 2)
- Same as above Mimeographed and a clipping (Folder 3)
- Texts concerning a Danubian Federation. Vicissitudes of East Central European Unity. (WW I and the Peace Settlement) Large folder contains a number of folders on same subject (Folder 4)
- W. Hallstein. Economic Integration as a factor of political Unification (BOOKLET) (Folder 5)
- Papers Concerning Plans of an East European Federation (Folder 6)
- Eastern Europe and Used Material (Folder 7)
- Katolikus Szemle. Roma, 2. (BOOKLET), 1980 (Folder 8)
- Struggle of World Forces along the Danube. Old Draft (Folder 9)
- Memorial Service for Oscar Jászi, Oberlin, Feb.23 1957 (Folder 10)
- Symposium, East Central Europe in World Politics Danubian Integration. Federácios Tervek. (Large folder, containing pertaining typewritten, mimeographed mat. and booklets.), Feb. 1959 (Folder 11)
- WITHDRAWN (Bundle BUNDLE XLII)
  - Kettos Járom Alatt. MAGAZINE, 1 ITEM ONLY
- Diplomacy in a Whirlpool. Hungarian Reviews, 1 Folder with Booklets and clippings (Box 27, Bundle BUNDLE XLIII)
- Miscellaneous material found grouped, but unidentified. Hungarian Studies publications mainly (Box 28, Bundle BUNDLE XLIV)
- Miscellaneous booklets, Mimeographed letters, found together but not identified. Mainly Hungarian Studies (Box 29, Bundle BUNDLE XLV)
- Typewritten Texts, working papers for unidentified book (Bundle BUNDLE XLVI)
- Unused passages concerning endeavors for East European Federation (Box 30, Bundle BUNDLE XLVII, Folder 1)
- Lecture Materials. Introduction to the First Project and Table of Contents (Folder 2)
- Epilogue. Danubian Federation. Auer material. Federation Plans in Eastern Danubian Europe (Folder 3)
- Between Russia and the West. Not published texts. Old Table of Contents and long text of old chapters. One to Three (Bundle BUNDLE XLVIII)
- WITHDRAWN (Bundle BUNDLE XIL)
  - Hungarian Diplomacy. Hungarian Diplomacy in the Power Politics of the Postwar Era, One folder
- Booklets and typed texts pert. to Roumania and Chechoslovakia (Box 30-31, Bundle BUNDLE L, Folder 1)
- Chechoslovak Material, WW I. and after (Folder 2)
- Czechoslovak cikk. A Nyugati Hatalmak Dunai Politikaja. My article in Courier de l'Occident. and correspondence on subsequent controversy, (15 October, 1949) (Folder 3)
- Checho. Material (Folder 4)
- Chechoslovak Material, ff, 1947 (Folder 5)
- 6a Magyar Csehszlovák viszony alapadatai. Délszlovákiai telepesek ügye után. Memoranda on Czechoslovak Materials, 1918-1945 1938
- 6b. My letter of May 1948 to William Neuman concerning my article on population exchange between Hungary and Czechoslovakia
- 6c Misc. booklets. Xerox on subject found in this order. Letter from Mrs. Henrietta Sirchich
- Misc. reprints of documents and clippings, found in this order (Folder 7)
- Correspondence with the Hungarian Chair in Bloomington. Hungarian History World History Conference (Box 32-33, Bundle BUNDLE LI, Folder 1)
- Paris and Malestroit This folder is not in this bundle it was put with "Correspondence grouping", May-July 1982 (Folder 2)
- Charlottsville Lecture texts., Sept. 17-24, 1983 (Folder 3)
- Lecture text. XVth Conference, Entitled Disarray and Reorientation (Bonn?) (Folder 4)
- University of Virginia conference material (Folder 5)
- Lectures in Hungarian. Hogyan jött létre a második Trianoni Béke. Békekötés a Második világháboru után. Elöadas a Magyar Külügyi Társaságban, N.Y. és az ben a Masodik Világháborut követö "Trianoni" tárgyalások és azok eredményei, 1977, Oct. 29 1970 (Folder 6)
- My papers delivered at international conferences in Germany and the USA and some related materials (Folder 7)
- Fifty years of Communism in Russia (BOOKLET AND LECTURE, TYPED) (Folder 8)
- US Business and Economic Relations with Eastern Europe. (Conference material), March 25-26, 1982 (Folder 9)
- American contribution to Diplomacy. The Impact of the American Revolution on European Diplomacy., 1776 (Folder 10)
- Misc. clippings found in this order (Folder 11)
- Small metal file-card box: Minority Population, Human rights, Internat. Relations, History, comp.Gov. European Federation, Russia & Communism (Box 33, Bundle BUNDLE LII)
- BOOKDS: Magyar Tájékoztató Zsebkönyvtár. R. Steggins: The US in World Affairs, 1950
- This folder put with "Correspondence grouping" (Bundle BUNDLE LIII, Folder 1)
- Auertol kapott anyag. Correspondence and Mimeographed material, Auer, Szegedy, Teleki Géza ügy. Level. Teleki Bélának. Kovács Imre levele, Vándor felszolalása. Kövér Memoranduma. Magyarország és a nyugati hatalmak. Nagy Ferenc, Eckhardt ugy. Barankovics (Folder 2)
- Correspondence, not here, in "Correspondence Grouping." (Folder 3)
- Barankovics. Full text sent to him. Kerston Committee: Correspondence concerning my introductory paper (Folder 4)
- Teleki életrajz (Folder 5)
- Kovrig Béla, javitások és levelezés (Folder 6)
- Tragedy of Transylvania. (PRINTED MATTER) (Box 34, Bundle BUNDLE LIV, Folder 1)
- Hungarians in Rumania. Erdely, an, New Yorkban kapott anyag és a román propaganda füzet, 1977 October 30 (Folder 2)
- Printed matter, found in this order (Folder 3)
- Correspondence, not in this bundle (Folder 4)
- 4a. Correspondence, not in this bundle
- Correspondence, not in this bundle (Folder 5)
- Correspondence and pertaining printed matter (Folder 6)
- Román anyag. 1. Auer beszede - 2. Le Probleme Hongrois par rapport a la Roumanie, Budapest, - 3. Magyar-Román viszony a Küm. Pol osztály által kiadott Értesitöben, -4. Az Irodalmi Ujsag erdélyi Melléklete március-április. 5. Deák István feljegyzése Bukaresti és kolozsvári látogatásáról, 1946 aug. 31 1946 1947-48 1977 (Folder 7)
- Rumania - Marice (?) Malinovsky Marshall irta alá a fegyverszüneti szerzödest a 3 Szövetséges H...(?) várban (Folder 8)
- Transylvanian Quarterly. No., October 1979
- Értesito. Kézirat. KUM Pol. Osztaly. II. Evf. 1-3 szam., 1948 Jan-Marc (Folder 9)
- Pol.oszt. értesitö. I. évf. 1 sz. 2-3 sz. és II évf. 103 sz. a csehszlovák anyagban van (Folder 10)
- Iratjegyzetek. Folder with listing of contents which is missing (Folder 11)
- Letters, aide memoirs, printed booklets, affidavits related to Prof. Kertész' ambassadorship in Rome, 1947-48 (Bundle BUNDLE LV)
- Liste de MM les membres du Corps Diplomatique., 1 Octobre 1946 (Box 35, Bundle BUNDLE LVI, Folder 1)
- Erfolge nach langen Mühen, (PRINTED ARTICLE), October 1980 (Folder 2)
- Handwritten draft listing. Invitation to come to US, NOT INCLUDED, 1948 (Folder 3)
- Data and Activities Documents. France, Rome 1947. Magyar Közlöny, Course in Paris 1948, 1946, 1948 (Folder 4)
- Review of Politics: Kertész: Expulsion of the Germans from Hungary, a Study of Postwar Diplomacy (REPRINT) (Folder 5)
- There is no No.6
- Ambasciate e Legazione Estere in Italia, (BOOKLET), Feb. 1947 (Folder 7)
- Weidlein. Hintergründe der Vertreibung der Deutschen aus Ungarn BOOKLET (Folder 8)
- Weidlein. Geschichte der Ungardeutschen in Dokumenten. BOOKLET, 1930-50 (Folder 9)
- Südost Stimmen. III Jahrgang, Nr. 5. Die Vertreibung der Deutschen aus Ungarn. (BOOKLET) (Bundle BUNDLE LVII, Folder 1)
- The Review of Politics. Vol.15, No.2. Kertész, The Expulsion of the Germans from Hungary. (BOOKLET), April 1953 (Folder 2)
- Misc. Printed matter. Mimeographed matter found in this order (Folder 3)
- Emlékiratom a Német kitelepitéssel kapcsolatos feljegyzése (Folder 4)
- Nemet Dossier Material relating to expulsions of Germans; also includes Mindszenty Pasztorlevél in 1945 (Bundle BUNDLE LVIII)
- Külügyminiszter. Folder. A magyarországi német lakosság kitelepitése tárgyában (Box 36, Bundle BUNDLE LIX, Folder 1)
- Same as above (Folder 2)
- Reparation Material Memorandum on reparation payments, stabilization of money and Eckhardt (?) Retz (?) evaluation of Hungary's financial condition (Folder 3)
- Aid Memoirs. Economic Chapters. (Originally in the US Diplomacy in a Whirlpool. Hungarian Economy and the Reparation Payments, 1945047 (Folder 4)
- Economics in Hungary. Reparations. Early Postwar Years, 1 folder (Bundle BUNDLE LX)
- Miscellaneous loose material found in this position. Draft of Chapter Four. Legacy from the First World War (Box 36, Bundle BUNDLE LXI)
- Loose papers, first draft of article (Bundle BUNDLE LXII, Folder 1)